너희 부모님 결혼 기념 파티에
누구 데려가도 돼?
Is it okay if I bring someone
to your parents' anniversary?
- 그럼
- 그래
-Sure.
-Yeah.
- 누군데?
- 파커야, 세탁소에서 만났어
-Who's the guy?
-Parker, we met at the cleaners.
네 팬티에 세탁용 풀 뿌려줬어?
Did he put a little starch
in your bloomers?
누구 주둥이야?
Who said that?
아니, 하지만 멋진 남자야
삶에 대한 열정이 대단하다고
No, he's really great, though.
He has this incredible zest for life.
날 여왕처럼 대해줘
물론 밤엔 거칠게 대해주지만
He treats me like a queen. Except
when he treats me like a naughty girl.
올해는 내가 건배 인사해도 돼?
Would it be okay if I give the toast?
20주년 때 그 일을 당하고도?
Even after what happened
at their 20th?
- 그래, 하고 싶어
- 엄마한테 야유나 당하지 마
-I'd really like to.
-Hopefully this time Mom won't boo you.
좋았어! 건배 인사는 매번 오빠가
했는데 다들 감동 받아 울더라고
Yes! Every year Ross makes the toast,
and it always makes them cry.
- 이번엔 내가 모두를 울릴 거야
- 왜 로스를 편애하는지 궁금해?
-This year, I'm gonna make them cry.
-You wonder why Ross is their favorite?
오빠가 건배 인사를 하면
다들 울며 오빠 등을 토닥여줬지
Any time Ross makes a toast, everyone
cries and pats him on the back.
엄마 아빤 나한테 이러고 말야
"어쩌면, 네 오빤 정말"
And they all come up to me and say,
"God, your brother."
올핸 뭐라고 하게 될 줄 알아?
"어쩌면, 넌 참"
You know what they're gonna say
this year? "God, you."
적어도 한 사람은 울테니 걱정마
Well, at least one
person will be crying.
난 배우잖아, 배우는 언제든
큐 사인 한방에 울수 있어
I'm an actor, and any actor
worth his salt can cry on cue.
- 정말? 정말이야?
- 농담해? 잘 봐
-Really? You can do that?
-Oh, you kidding me? Watch.
너희가 보고 있으니 못하겠잖아!
Well, I can't do it
with you guys watching me!
프렌즈 시즌 8
'결혼 35주년을 맞이한
겔러부부'
어서 와요
Hey.
세상에, 자기 정말 환상적이야
Oh, my God.
You look so fantastic.
오는 길에 자기 모습을
머리 속으로 상상했는데
On my way over,
I pictured you in my mind's eye.
이제 보니
'머리, 상상력 좀 더 키워!'네
Now I'm like,
"Mind's eye, you had no idea!"
- 다시 해요!
- 좋아
-Let's do that again!
-Okay.
- 뭐 해?
- 건배 인사 준비해
-What are you doing?
-I'm working on my toast.
아니지, '2002 노아의 홍수'야
Or as I like to call it:
"Sob-fest 2002."
아주 기대가 돼
I cannot wait to see them cry.
애정의 조건을 보고 있는
기분이 들 거라고
It's not gonna be like regular crying. It's
gonna be like Terms of Endearment crying.
두 분이 콧물을 줄줄 흘리며
몸을 부르르 떨며...
I'm gonna reduce my parents
to sniffling, quaking masses of..
어릴때 두 분이
상처준게 있나 봐
I may have some unresolved anger
from my childhood.
- 이것 좀 봐
- 개잖아
-Hey, check this out.
-It's a dog.
죽은 개야
It's a dead dog.
이름이 치치인데 내가
고등학교 다닐 때 죽었어
Chi-Chi. She died
when I was in high school.
- 죽은 개 얘길 하려고?
- 멋있지?
-You're talking about a dead pet?
-It's good stuff, huh?
조이? 우리 부모님한테 줄
선물을 준비했어?
Joey? You got a present
for my parents?
결혼 35주년이잖아
내가 공로상을 만들어봤어
In honor of their 35th anniversary,
I had a star named after them.
- 멋있다
- 그리고 이건 노인용 카마수트라
-That is so cool.
-And I got Kama Sutra for the Elderly.
선물은 그냥 하나로 족할 것 같아
You know, I think maybe
the one present is enough.
- 리본 남은 거 있어?
- 그럼
-Do you guys have any extra ribbon?
-Sure.
어떤 걸로 줄까? 레이스, 공단,
면수자, 라피아, 깅엄, 펠트
What do you need? We got lace,
satin, sateen, raffia, gingham, felt..
내 고환도 이 안에 들었는지 몰라
And I think my testicles
may be in here too.
치치! 내가 정말로 좋아했던 개야
Chi-Chi! Oh, I loved this dog.
모니카가 치아 교정을 못 받은 건
치치가 수술이 필요했기 때문이야
Monica couldn't get braces
because Chi-Chi needed knee surgery.
- 뭐?
- 네가 올라타 무릎이 박살났잖아!
-What?
-You're the 200-pounder who rode her!
안녕! 얘들아, 이쪽은 파커야
파커, 이쪽은...
Hey! Everybody, this is Parker.
Parker, this is..
말하지 마, 내가 맞혀볼게
조이, 모니카, 로스, 레이첼...
No, don't tell me. Let me guess:
Joey, Monica, Ross, Rachel..
미안한데 피비가
당신 얘긴 안했어요
and I'm sorry,
Phoebe didn't mention you.
챈들러, 농담이에요! 마음에 들어
Chandler, I'm kidding!
Already you're my favorite.
- 각자 소개 좀 해봐요
- 실은 지금 나가야 돼요
-Tell me a little about yourselves.
-Actually, we should get going.
그 유명한 로스의 대사야!
Classic Ross!
레이첼, 빛이 나는군요!
만져봐도 돼요?
Rachel, look how you glow! May I?
벌써 만지고 있잖아요
I think you already are.
레이첼, 당신 몸 안에서
생명이 자라고 있어요
Rachel, you have life
growing inside you.
이것보다 더 기적적인 일이...
개 사진이네! 누구죠?
Is there anything more miraculous..
A picture of a dog! Whose is this?
옛날에 키우던 개인데
오래 전에 죽었어요
That's my old dog.
He passed away years ago.
그래도 인연이 닿았으니 행운이죠
멍멍, 옛 친구, 멍멍
Well, at least you were lucky to have
him. Bow-wow, old friend. Bow-wow.
얘들아, 정말로 지금 출발해야 돼
You guys, we really should get going.
어쩔까나, 내 명대사가 또 나왔네
There I go again, my catch phrase.
- 파티장은 어디에 있죠?
- 마사피쿠아요
-So where's the party?
-It's in Massapequa.
마사피쿠아, 신비롭게 들리네
인디언 역사와 관련이 있나요?
Massapequa, it sounds magical. Is it
steeped in Native American history?
인디언 천막은
햄버거 가게에 있어요
Well, there is an Arby's
in the shape of a tepee.
건배 인사는 여깄고 선물 챙겼어?
I've got my notes. You got the presents?
- 차 열쇠 여깄어
- 운전하고 가요? 좋았어
-I've got the car keys.
-We're driving? Aces.
- 괜찮은 친구 같네
- 그래, 아주 맘에 들어
-So he seems like a nice guy.
-Yeah, I like him a lot.
- 우리끼리 택시 타고 갈래?
- 안 그럼 안 갈 거야
-You want to hang back and take a cab?
-Okay, otherwise I'm not going.
- 엄마
- 파티가 너무 멋져요!
-Hey, Mom.
-This is such a great party!
35년이라니 굉장하네요
삶의 지혜 같은 거 없으세요?
Thirty-five years. Impressive.
Do you have any pearls of wisdom?
- 잭?
- 왜 이쑤시개에 음식을 꽂아주지?
-Jack?
-Why serve food on such a sharp stick?
좋은 질문이에요, 아빠
좋은 질문이에요
It's a good question, Dad.
It's a good question.
- 두 사람 축하해
- 감사합니다, 저희도 흥분돼요
-Congratulations, you two.
-Thank you, we're so excited.
결혼한 것도 정말 축하하고 말야
And also, congratulations
on your wedding.
- 잠깐 나 좀 볼래?
- 네
-Can we talk to you for just a moment?
-Yeah.
별일 아냐
It's just a little thing.
우린 너희들이 사생아를
낳게 돼 아주 기쁘다만
While we think it's marvelous you're
having this baby out of wedlock..
우리 친구들은 좀 구식이잖니
our friends are less open-minded.
- 너희들 결혼했다고 했어
- 네?
-We told them you're married.
-What?
협조해줘서 고맙구나
Thanks for going along with this.
- 결혼했다고 거짓말하라고요?
- 난 오늘 귀털을 면도했다
-We have to pretend that we're married?
-I had to shave my ears.
넌 할 수 있어
You can do this.
- 믿어져?
- 그러게
-Can you believe that?
-I know.
귀털 깎은 김에 콧털도 깎지
If you do the ears, you may as well
take a pass at the nose.
난 결혼했다고 거짓말하기 싫어
I don't want to have to lie
about being married.
나도, 하지만 두 분 파티잖아
딱 하루뿐이야
I don't either. But it's their party,
and it's one night.
거짓말할 필요도 없어
그냥 아무 말 마
We don't have to lie.
We won't talk.
누가 뭐라면 웃으며
고개만 끄덕이는 거야
If it comes up,
we'll smile, we'll nod along..
- 로스?
- 레이첼?
-Ross?
-Rachel?
리사 숙모, 댄 삼촌
Hi, Aunt Lisa. Uncle Dan.
임신 축하한다, 또 결혼도 말야
Congratulations on the baby
and on the wedding.
- 출발하는 데 보태 쓰거라
- 결혼 생활은 어떠니?
-Here's something to start you out.
-How's marriage treating you?
- 세상에, 굉장해요!
- 너무 좋아요
-Unbelievable. It's great!
-We love marriage.
나중에 보자
We'll see you later.
- 어서 와!
- 안녕!
-Hey!
-Hi!
모니카, 운전을 정말 잘하더군요
Can I just say, Monica,
that your driving is exquisite.
고마워요, 아까 말했듯이
차선만 잘 지키면 돼요
Thanks. Like I said before,
I pretty much just stayed in the lines..
사람 안 치게 조심하고요
and tried not to hit anybody.
아름다운 곳이군요
아름다운 밤이에요
What a beautiful place.
What a great night.
당신들과 함께
이 행사장에 있는 이 느낌
I have to tell you, being here
with all of you in Event Room C..
너무 행복해요
이곳의 역사가 느껴져요
I feel so lucky. Think of the good
times that happened here.
생일 파티, 졸업 무도회,
유대교 행사, 그 흥청거림!
The birthdays, the proms,
the mitzvahs, both bar and bat!
지금과 비하면 아무것도 아니죠
이 순간을 기억하고 싶어요
None will compare with tonight.
I don't want to forget it.
내 머리 속 사진기로
찍어두고 싶어요, 찰칵
It's like I want to take a mental
picture of you all. Click.
플래시가 안 터졌어요
I don't think the flash went off.
- 화장실 갔다올게요
- 같이 가요
-I'm gonna find the men's room.
-I'll go with you.
누가 가서 마취총이랑
Somewhere there is someone
with a tranquilizer gun..
방충망 좀 구해 갖고 와
and a huge butterfly net looking
for that man.
나도 화장실 가고 싶은데
내 물건 보면 감탄할 거야
I have to go too, but I don't
want him complimenting my thing.
따로 온 게 다행이지
차안에서도 저랬어?
Glad we weren't in the car.
Did he let up?
롱아일랜드 고속도로가
'콘크리트의 기적'이래
He called the Long lsland
Expressway a "concrete miracle."
이 방, 이 밤
This room. This night.
저 웨이터! 저 신발!
머리 속 사진기로 찍어놔야지!
That waiter! His shoes!
I must take a mental picture!
미안해
Sorry.
파커를 흉보고 있었어?
Were you guys making fun of Parker?
얼마나 엿들었는지에 따라 달라
That depends, how much did you hear?
좀 열정적이라 그래, 그럼 안 돼?
He's a little enthusiastic.
What's wrong with that?
- 조금이 아니지
- 그래서? 내가 좋아해
-It's so much.
-Well, so what? I like him.
내가 언제 네 애인들 흉보디?
태그, 재니스, 모나
Do I make fun of the people you date?
Tag, Janice, Mona.
아니, 왜냐하면 우린 친구거든
나도 솔직히 말해볼까?
No, because friends don't do that.
Do you want my opinion?
너흰 누가 인간 쓰레기랑 사귀나
서로 경쟁하는 것 같아!
Your collective dating record reads
like a who's who of human crap!
- 우리가 잘못했어
- 맞아
-I feel terrible.
-I know.
모나가 어때서 저래?
What was wrong with Mona?
- 열어봐, 어서
- 따봉!
-Open it, open it, open it.
-Yeah, baby!
우리도 모르는 새 결혼을 했구나
So we never got to hear
about your wedding.
- 결혼식에 초대를 했어야지
- 조촐하게 가족만 초대했어요
-We were surprised we weren't invited.
-No, it was a small wedding.
하지만 아름다웠죠
조촐하지만 화려했어요
But it was beautiful.
It was small, but kind of spectacular.
- 어디서 했는데?
- 바베이도스요, 석양 아래서
-Where did you have it?
-On a cliff in Barbados, at sunset.
신부 입장할 때 스티비 원더가
'아름다운 그녀'를 불렀죠
And Stevie Wonder sang " lsn't She
Lovely" as I walked down the aisle.
- 부모님이 스티비랑 친구예요
- 세상에, 굉장하네
-Stevie's a family friend.
-Oh, my God. That's amazing.
- 사진을 보고 싶구나
- 네, 저도 그래요
-I'd love to see pictures.
-Yeah, so would I.
그런데 애니 리보위츠가
필름 넣는 걸 깜박했지 뭐예요
You wouldn't think Annie Liebowitz
would forget to put film in the camera.
잠깐 실례해도 될까요?
Would you excuse us for a second?
- 뭐 하는 거야?
- 너완 달리 난 한번뿐인 결혼이야
-What are you doing?
-What? This may be my only wedding.
- 근사하게 하고 싶다고
- 좋아, 그럼 난
-And I want it to be amazing.
-Okay.
- 오토바이 타고 입장했다고 할게
- 로스, 현실감 있게 해
-Maybe I rode in on a Harley.
-Ross, it has to be realistic.
괜찮아? 어쩐지 조용한 것 같네
Say, are you okay?
You seem kind of quiet.
- 좋아요, 당신과 함께 있잖아요
- 나도 그래, 정말 행복해!
-No, I'm fine. I'm great. I'm with you.
-And I'm with you. What a great time!
이 접시 카트 좀 봐
Look at this plate bouncy thing.
일손을 줄인 대단한 발명품이야
What an inspired solution to man's
plate-dispensing problems.
- 굴이네! '아' 해봐
- 됐어요
Oysters! Let me feed you.
That's not necessary.
- 하나만?
- 싫어요
-Please?
-I don't eat..
- 먹을 때까지 포기 안 할 거야
- 알았어요, 먹을게요
-I won't quit until you try one.
-Okay, fine.
- 좋네요
- 맛이 어때? 난 굴 안 먹어
-Good.
-What're they like? I've never had one.
- 먹어봐요
- 됐어, 징그럽게 생겼어
-Try one.
-They look too weird.
나도 알아요
I know, I know.
자기 가족들 나한테 관심이 많아
Listen, your family is really
starting to warm up to me.
저 여잔 파티 요리사야
You just kissed the caterer.
- 뭐 해?
- 건배 준비, 두 분 뜻밖일걸
-What are you doing?
-Going over my toast.
너무 기대돼, 너무 울어서
숨쉬기조차 힘들 거라고
I can't wait. They'll cry so hard,
they'll be fighting for breath.
건배 없이도
숨 못 쉬게 할 수 있어
If you want to, I could just
hold them down and you could just..
눈먼 벨기에 수녀가 만든
레이스 면사포였어요
And my veil was lace,
made by blind Belgian nuns.
- 장님이라고?
- 면사포 만들다 그렇게 됐죠
-Blind?
-Not at first, but it's intricate work.
눈을 희생할 가치가 있을 만큼
아름다운 면사포 였거든요
They said even though they lost
their sight, it was worth it.
- 정말 예뻤겠네
- 전 잘 모르겠어요
-I bet you looked beautiful.
-Well, I don't know.
하지만 사람들 말로는
제가 천사 같았다고 하더군요
But there were some people that said
I looked like a floating angel.
- 어떻게 청혼했어?
- 그게 또 끝내준답니다
-How did you propose?
-Oh, yeah, that's a great story.
레이첼을 천문관으로 데려갔어요
Well, actually, I took her
to the planetarium.
우리가 맨 처음 데이트 한 곳이죠
That's where we had our first date.
레이첼이 좋아하는 백합을
천문관 안에 쫙 뿌렸어요
I had the room filled with lilies,
her favorite flower.
- 너무 멋있어!
- 끝까지 좀 듣자고요!
-That is so sweet!
-I want to hear the rest!
그런 다음 프레드 아스테어의
'더 웨이 유 룩 투나잇'을 틀고
Then Fred Astaire singing,
"The Way You Look Tonight" came on..
불을 다 끈 다음 무릎을 꿇었어요
the lights came down,
I got on one knee..
그때 천장에 별들이 이렇게 떴죠
and written across the dome,
in the stars, were the words:
"결혼해주겠어?"
"Will you marry me?"
반지가 주먹만했다니까요
And the ring was the size of my fist.
피비, 저기 말야
Hey, Phoebe? Look..
아까 일은 사과하고 싶어
우리가 바보 같았어
I want to apologize. Okay?
We were being jerks.
- 파커랑 친해지고 싶어
- 그럼 서둘러
-Parker's nice, I'd like to know him.
-You better do it now.
- 왜?
- 내가 파커를 죽일 거거든
-Why?
-Because I'm gonna kill him.
- 뭐?
- 너희가 맞아, 너무 호들갑이야
-What?
-He's too excited about everything.
나도 꽤 열정적이지만
이건 두 분 35주년 파티라고
I'm all for living, but this is
the Gellers' 35th anniversary.
까놓고 말해서 너무 형편없어
Let's call a spade a spade.
This party stinks.
맞아, 진짜 최악이야
I'm having the worst time.
뷔페에 한참 줄 서있다
드디어 접시 있는 데 갔더니
There was a line for the buffet,
and when I got to the plates..
발 밑에 큰 코딱지가 있지 뭐야
I slipped on a giant booger.
굴 아니었어?
Are you sure it wasn't an oyster?
몰라, 자세히 안 봤어
It could've been.
I didn't look at it.
그냥 챈들러 코트 밟고 비볐거든
I wiped it on Chandler's coat
and got the hell out.
난 멋진 남자인 줄 알았어
너무 행복했었다고
I thought he was a great guy.
I was so excited about him.
그러지 마, 계속 행복해해도 돼
Well, hey, you should
be excited about him.
괜찮은 남자라니까, 좋은 친구야
There's nothing wrong with him.
- 정말?
- 그럼, 솔직히 말해서
-You think?
-Yeah, know what?
- 우리가 너무 부정적이었어
- 맞아
-We were all just being too negative.
-You're right.
인생을 즐기는 것 뿐이야
우리 모두 파커처럼 돼야 한다고
He's just embracing life. We could
all stand to be more like Parker.
난 파커가 좋아!
난 긍정적인 사람이라고!
You know what? I'm like him!
I'm a positive person!
- 그건 좀 어폐가 있다
- 어폐라니?
-Actually, you have an edge.
-What's that?
- 파커다!
- 봐, 기차 댄스야!
-Oh, it's Parker!
-Look, the Bunny Hop!
- 너무 좋아요!
- 정말?
-Oh, I love it!
-You do?
농담해요? 사람들이 동물처럼
음악에 맞춰 흔드는데? 만세!
Are you kidding? People acting
like animals to music? Come on!
자, 건배할 시간입니다
Okay, it's time for the toast.
건배 인사는 늘 오빠가 했지만
올해는 제가 할 거예요
I know normally Ross gives the toast,
but this year I'll do it.
아주 감동적일 거예요
No, it's gonna be great. Really.
좋아요
Okay.
엄마, 아빠, 제가 결혼할 때
Mom, Dad, when I got married..
자신할 수 있었던 것 단 하나는
두 분처럼 살면 된다는 거였어요
the thing that made me sure I could
do it was the example you two set.
지금까지 제게 해준 모든 것
정말 고마워요
For that, and other things,
I want to thank you.
이 말은 아무리 해도
충분하지 않을 거예요
I know I probably don't
say it enough..
사랑해요
but I love you.
여기 이러고 있으니 이 자리에
못 오신 분이 생각나 슬프네요
When I look around, I'm saddened by the
thought of those who could not be here.
사랑하는 나나 할머니,
꼭 참석하셨어야 했는데
Nana, my beloved grandmother,
who would so want to be here.
안타깝게도
But she can't..
돌아가셨죠
because she's dead.
우리 개 치치도 마찬가지고요
As is our dog, Chi-Chi.
정말 귀엽게 생겼죠, 생겼었죠
I mean, look how cute she is.. was.
부모님께 전해주세요
Do me a favor,
pass this to my parents.
치치는 죽었어요
치치, 나나, 모두 갔다고요
Remember she's dead, okay?
Her and Nana, gone.
우와!
Wow!
애정의 조건에서
Does anybody remember when..
데브라 윙어가 애들과
헤어지던 장면 기억나세요?
Debra Winger had to say goodbye to
her children in Terms of Endearment?
못 보셨어요?
Didn't see that?
영화팬이 없네!
No movie fans?!
슬픈 얘기 들려드려요?
You want to hear something sad?
요전 날 60분을 봤는데
루마니아에 있는 고아들은
I was watching a 60 Minutes
piece on orphans in Romania..
너무 소외된 채 자라나
사랑이 뭔지도 모른대요
who have been so neglected
that they were incapable of love.
다들 돌심장이군요!
You people are made of stone!
맘대로 해요, 엄마 아빠를 위해!
Here's to Mom and Dad. Whatever!
고맙다, 아주 흥미로운 건배였어
Thank you, Monica.
That was interesting.
- 안 그래요, 잭?
- 왜 이 개가 기억이 안 나지?
-Wasn't it interesting, Jack?
-Why don't I remember this dog?
로스, 이번엔 네가 하지 그러니?
Ross? Why don't you give us
your toast now?
아녜요, 올해는 모니카가
하기로 했거든요
Oh, no, Mom.
It's just Monica this year.
그래서 안 한다고?
우리 결혼 35주년인데?
You're not saying anything?
On our 35th wedding anniversary?
알았어요
No, of course.
여러분, 잠깐 몇 마디만 할게요
Everybody? I just wanted to say..
제 신부인 레이첼을 대신해서요
on behalf of my new bride, Rachel..
저희들은
and myself, that if..
앞으로 35년 후
지금 두 분의 반만이라도
if in 35 years, we're half
as happy as you guys are..
행복할 수 있다면
큰 행운일 거라 생각해요
we'll count ourselves
the luckiest people in the world.
로스
Oh, Ross.
어머님이 살아서
저걸 들으셨어야 했어
I just wish Nana were alive
to hear Ross' toast.
세상에, 복도 등이 정말 기막혀
My God, what a fantastically
well-lit hallway.
뭐 좀 마실래요?
물이랑 진정제 줘요?
Can I get you something to drink,
like a water and Valium?
이 아파트 말야, 정말...
적당한 말이 없어
I must say, this apartment,
it's.. there are no words.
- 하나님, 감사합니다
- 안식처 같아
-Thank God.
-It's a haven.
- 3층의 현대판 에덴 동산이야
- 네, 알아요, 안다고요
-A third-floor paradise, a modern Eden.
-Yeah, I know, I know. Gotcha.
이봐요, 우리 좀 쉬는 게 어때요?
둘이 함께 조용히 앉아있는 거죠
Listen, why don't we just sit and
relax, just be with each other quietly.
좋아
That sounds great.
이렇게 편한 소파는 처음 봤어
This is the most comfortable couch
I've ever sat on.
다른 걸 해보죠, 우리 게임해요
Let's try something.
Let's play a game.
- 나 게임 좋아해
- 놀라워라
-I love games.
-Shocking.
어떤 게임이냐면
Let's play the game of..
'누가 말없이 오래 버티나'예요
who can stay quiet the longest.
젱가로 해
Or Jenga.
이것부터 먼저 해요
먼저 말하면 지는 거예요
Let's play this one first, and
remember, whoever talks first loses.
- 내가 졌어, 젱가 해
- 맙소사
-I lose, now Jenga.
-Oh, my God.
- 무슨 문제 있어?
- '문제'란 말도 다 알아요?
-Is something wrong?
-You know the word "wrong"?
모든 게 완벽하고 멋진 사람이?
Everything isn't perfect or magical?
모든 게 동화 나라의 마법처럼
느껴지는 사람이?
Everything isn't aglow
with the light of fairies?
아까 그건 브레이크 등이었다고요!
They were just brake lights, Parker!
교통 혼잡을 재미있게
표현한 것 뿐이야
Excuse me for putting a good spin
on a traffic jam.
모든 걸 다 재미있게
표현할 필요는 없어요!
You don't have to put
a good spin on everything!
- 미안해, 긍정적이라 그래
- 아뇨, 긍정적인 건 나예요
-I'm sorry. I'm a positive person.
-No, I'm a positive person.
당신은 항우울제 먹은
산타클로스라고요
You are like Santa Claus on Prozac.
디즈니랜드에서
섹스하는 사람 같다고요!
At Disneyland, getting laid!
왜 그래? 내가 부정적이길 원해?
좀 덜 행복했으면 좋겠어?
You want me to be negative?
You want me to be less happy?
아주 많이요
Much less happy.
좋아, 그럼 로스 버전으로
"난 가는 게 좋겠어"
Fine. Well, then to quote Ross,
"I better be going."
잘 가요!
So long!
세상에서 제일 멋진 문에
엉덩이 안 끼게 조심해요
Don't let the "best door in the world"
hit you in the ass on your way out.
우리 방금 싸움한 거
너무 멋있지 않았어?
Isn't this the most incredible fight
you've had in your life?
오토바이 사이드카에 널 태우고
피로연장으로 가는 거지
We could've gone from the ceremony to
the reception with you in the sidecar.
현실감이 전혀 없어
It just isn't feasible.
비둘기가 네 손에 반지를
끼워주는 건 현실감 있고
But a dove placing the ring on your
finger would've been no problem.
- 오늘밤 결혼하느라 재밌었어
- 그래, 쉽게 4백 불도 벌고
-It was fun being married to you.
-Yeah, and it was an easy 400 bucks.
- 뭐 하나 물어봐도 돼?
- 그래
-Okay, Ross, can I ask you something?
-Yeah.
- 그 천문관 청혼 있잖아?
- 알아, 너무 바보 같았어
-That proposal at the planetarium?
-I know, I know. It was stupid.
농담해? 백합에다가
그 노래, 그 별까지?
Are you kidding? With the lilies,
and the song and the stars?
정말이지 너무 멋있었어
네가 지어낸 거야?
It was really wonderful.
Did you just make that up?
우리가 사귈 때 생각했던 거야
I thought of it
when we were going out.
청혼하게 되면 그렇게 하려고
That's how I imagined
I would ask you to marry me.
와
Wow.
그렇게 청혼했으면
거절하기 힘들었을 거야
Well, that would've been
very hard to say no to.
청혼 안 한 게 다행이었어
결혼 비용이 장난 아니었을 테니
It's a good thing I didn't do it, it
sounds like a very expensive wedding.
- 그래, 잘 자
- 너도
-Okay, good night.
-Good night.
사이드카에 스크린을 달아
머리 안 날리게 해도 안 될까?
Even if the sidecar had a windscreen
to protect your hair?
- 생각해볼게
- 더는 욕심 안 부려
-I will think about it.
-That's all I'm asking.
좋아, 그만 포기할래
Okay, that's it. I give up.
엄마 아빠 결혼 40주년 땐
오빠가 건배 인사해
At Mom and Dad's 40th anniversary,
you give the speech.
왜 아무도 안 울었나 몰라
네 인사는 아주 좋았어
You know, I don't understand
why they didn't cry.
- 됐어
- 그 사랑에 대한 얘기?
-Come on.
-That stuff you said about true love?
네 말이 맞아, 엄마 아빠한테
우린 많은 걸 배웠다고
You were right. We did learn
a lot from Mom and Dad.
그리고 그 장난기 가득한
치치의 사진 하며
That picture of Chi-Chi
with her mischievous grin.
할머니 얘기도 그렇잖아
오셨으면 참 좋았을 거라고
And what you said about Nana? Yeah,
she really would've wanted to be there.
있잖아
And you know what?
와 계셨던 것 같아
I think she was.
맙소사, 대체 어떻게 하는 거야?
Oh, good God, Ross,
how the hell do you do it?